readyship.co 2019-12-20

# Privacy Policy | Ready-Made WordPress Marketplace - ReadyShip

_Your privacy is critically important to us. At ReadyShip, we have a few fundamental principles:_

  * We are thoughtful about the personal information we ask you to provide and the personal information that we collect about you through the operation of our services.
  * We store personal information for only as long as we have a reason to keep it.
  * We aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what information on your website is shared publicly (or kept private), indexed by search engines, and permanently deleted.
  * We help protect you from overreaching government demands for your personal information.
  * We aim for full transparency on how we gather, use, and share your personal information.  
Below is our Privacy Policy, which incorporates and clarifies these principles.

### Who We Are and What This Policy Covers

Hi there, we are ReadyShip. A platform that enables people to buy/sell Ready-Made WordPress sites as a subscription service model with Managed WordPress hosting. We believe that our platform will make a lot of people happy.   
This Privacy Policy applies to information that we collect about you when you use ReadyShip.  
Below we explain how we collect, use, and share information about you, along with the choices that you have with respect to that information.

### Information We Collect

We only collect information about you if we have a reason to do so–for example, to provide our Services, to communicate with you, or to make our Services better.  
We collect information in three ways: if and when you provide information to us, automatically through operating our Services, and from outside sources. Let’s go over the information that we collect.

####  _Information You Provide To Us_

It’s probably no surprise that we collect information that you provide to us. The amount and type of information depends on the context and how we use the information. Here are some examples:

  *  **Basic Account Information:** We ask for basic information from you in order to set up your account. For example, we require individuals who sign up for buyer account to provide a username, email and password. We require individuals who sign up for seller account to provide email, password, name, country and currency. You may provide us with more information like company name or website URL but we don’t require that information to create a seller account.
  *  **Public Profile Information:** If you have an account with us, we collect the information that you provide for your public profile. For example if you have a seller account, your username is part of that public profile, along with any other information you put into your public profile, such as photo, website URL, profile text etc. Your public profile information is just that–public–so please keep that in mind when deciding what information you would like to include.
  *  **Transaction and Billing Information:** If you want to buy a Ready-Made WordPress site you will have to provide us additional personal and payment information that is required to process the transaction and your payment, such as card information, address, country, state and postal code.

####  _Information We Collect Automatically_

We also collect some information automatically:

  *  **Log Information:** Like most online service providers, we collect information that web browsers, mobile devices, and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, IP address, unique device identifiers, language preference, referring site, the date and time of access, operating system, and mobile network information. We collect log information when you use our Services–for example, when you create or make changes to your existing products.
  *  **Usage Information:** We collect information about your usage of our Services. For example, we collect information about the actions that users perform on our platform like sign in and sign out, product create, website create etc. We use this information so we can get insights on how people use our Services, so we can make our Services better.
  *  **Location Information:** We may determine the approximate location of your device from your IP address. We collect and use this information to, for example, calculate how many people visit our Services from certain geographic regions.
  *  **Information From Cookies:** A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. We use cookies to help us identify and track visitors, usage and access preferences for our Services.

### How And Why We Use Information

####  _Purposes for Using Information_

We use information about you as mentioned above and for the purposes listed below:

  * To provide our Services–for example, to set up and maintain your account, host your website, backup and restore your website, or charge you for any of our paid Services;
  * To further develop and improve our Services–for example by adding new features that we think our users will enjoy or will help them to create and manage their websites more efficiently;
  * To monitor and analyze trends and better understand how users interact with our Services, which helps us improve our Services and make them easier to use;
  * To measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition–for example, we may analyze how many individuals purchased a plan after receiving a marketing message or the features used by those who continue to use our Services after a certain length of time;
  * To monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, protect the security of our Services, detect and prevent fraudulent transactions and other illegal activities, fight spam, and protect the rights and property of ReadyShip and others, which may result in us declining a transaction or the use of our Services;
  * To communicate with you, for example through an email, about offers and promotions offered by ReadyShip and others we think will be of interest to you, solicit your feedback, or keep you up to date on ReadyShip and our products; and
  * To personalize your experience using our Services, provide content recommendation, target our marketing messages to groups of our users (for example, those who have a particular plan with us or have been our user for a certain length of time), and serve relevant advertisements.

####  _Legal Bases for Collecting and Using Information_

A note here for those in the European Union about our legal grounds for processing information about you under EU data protection laws, which is that our use of your information is based on the grounds that:

  * The use is necessary in order to fulfill our commitments to you under our Terms of Service or other agreements with you or is necessary to administer your account–for example, in order to enable access to our website on your device or charge you for a paid plan; or
  * The use is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation; or
  * The use is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or those of another person; or
  * We have a legitimate interest in using your information–for example, to provide and update our Services, to improve our Services so that we can offer you an even better user experience, to safeguard our Services, to communicate with you, to measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition, to monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, and to personalize your experience; or
  * You have given us your consent–for example before we place certain cookies on your device and access and analyze them later on.

### Sharing Information

####  _How We Share Information_

We do not sell our users’ private personal information.  
We share information about you in the limited circumstances spelled out below and with appropriate safeguards on your privacy:

  *  **Subsidiaries, Employees, and Independent Contractors:** We may disclose information about you to our subsidiaries, our employees, and individuals who are our independent contractors that need to know the information in order to help us provide our Services or to process the information on our behalf. We require our subsidiaries, employees, and independent contractors to follow this Privacy Policy for personal information that we share with them.
  *  **Third Party Vendors:** We may share information about you with third party vendors who need to know information about you in order to provide their services to us, or to provide their services to you or your site. This group includes vendors that help us provide our Services to you (like payment providers that process your credit and debit card information, fraud prevention services that allow us to analyze fraudulent payment transactions, postal and email delivery services that help us stay in touch with you, customer chat and email support services that help us communicate with you, registrars, registries, and data escrow services that allow us to provide domain registration services, and your hosting provider if your site is not hosted by ReadyShip), those that assist us with our marketing efforts (e.g. by providing tools for identifying a specific marketing target group or improving our marketing campaigns), those that help us understand and enhance our Services (like analytics providers), who may need information about you in order to, for example, provide technical or other support services to you. We require vendors to agree to privacy commitments in order to share information with them.
  *  **Legal Requests:** We may disclose information about you in response to a subpoena, court order, or other governmental request.
  *  **To Protect Rights, Property and Others:** We may disclose information about you when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of ReadyShip, third parties, or the public at large. For example, if we have a good faith belief that there is an imminent danger of death or serious physical injury, we may disclose information related to the emergency without delay.
  *  **Business Transfers:** In connection with any merger, sale of company assets, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company, or in the unlikely event that ReadyShip goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would likely be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. If any of these events were to happen, this Privacy Policy would continue to apply to your information and the party receiving your information may continue to use your information, but only consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  *  **With Your Consent:** We may share and disclose information with your consent or at your direction. For example, we may share your information with third parties with which you authorize us to do so, such as the social media services that you connect to your site, product or profile information through our platform.
  *  **Aggregated or De-Identified Information:** We may share information that has been aggregated or reasonably de-identified, so that the information could not reasonably be used to identify you. For instance, we may publish aggregate statistics about the use of our Services and we may share a hashed version of your email address to facilitate customized ad campaigns on other platforms.
  *  **Publish Support Requests:** And if you send us a request (for example, via a support email or one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish that request in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users.

####  _Information Shared Publicly_

Information that you choose to make public is–you guessed it–disclosed publicly.  
That means, of course, that information like your public profile, posts, other content that you make public on your product/website, are all available to others and we hope you get a lot of views.   
Public information may also be indexed by search engines or used by third parties.  
Please keep all of this in mind when deciding what you would like to share.

### How Long we keep Information

We generally discard information about you when we no longer need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it–which are described in the section above on How and Why We Use Information–and we are not legally required to continue to keep it.  
As another example, when you delete a post, page, or comment from your WordPress.com site, it stays in your Trash folder for thirty days just in case you change your mind and would like restore that content–because starting again from scratch is no fun, at all. After the thirty days are up, the deleted content may remain on our backups and caches until purged.

### Security

While no online service is 100% secure, we work very hard to protect information about you against unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction, and take reasonable measures to do so, such as monitoring our Services for potential vulnerabilities and attacks.

### Choices

You have several choices available when it comes to information about you:

  *  **Limit the Information that You Provide:** If you have an account with us, you can choose not to provide the optional account, profile and payment information. Please keep in mind that if you do not provide some of this information certain features of our Services, for example extended trial period, may not be accessible.
  *  **Opt-Out of Electronic Communications:** You may choose not to subscribe to our newsletter mail campaign so you will not receive any promotional messages. However we may still send you other messages, like those about your account and legal notices.
  *  **Set Your Browser to Reject Cookies:** You can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies before using our platform, with the drawback that certain features of our platform may not function properly without the aid of the cookies.
  *  **Close Your Account:** While we’d be very sad to see you go, if you no longer want to use our Services, you can close your ReadyShip account. Please keep in mind that we may continue to retain your information after closing your account, as described in How Long We Keep Information above–for example, when that information is reasonably needed to comply with (or demonstrate our compliance with) legal obligations such as law enforcement requests, or reasonably needed for our legitimate business interests.

### Your Rights

If you are located in certain countries, including those that fall under the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (AKA the “GDPR”), data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions provided by the law, including the rights to:

  * Request access to your personal data;
  * Request correction or deletion of your personal data;
  * Object to our use and processing of your personal data;
  * Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data; and
  * Request portability of your personal data.  
You can usually access, correct, or delete your personal data using your account settings and tools that we offer, but if you aren’t able to do that, or you would like to contact us about one of the other rights, please do not hesitate to contact us via our support email support@readyship.co.  
EU individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

### Other Things You Should Know

####  _Third Party Software_

If you’d like to use third party plugins, or other third party software, please keep in mind that when you interact with them you may provide information about yourself (or your site visitors) to those third parties. We don’t own or control these third parties and they have their own rules about collection, use and sharing of information, which you should review.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, ReadyShip may change its Privacy Policy from time to time. ReadyShip encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the change log below, and, in some cases, we may provide additional notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage or our blog, or sending you a notification through email or your dashboard). Your further use of the Services after a change to our Privacy Policy will be subject to the updated policy.  
That’s it! Thanks for reading.

### License of this document.

This document is based on Automattic Inc’s Privacy Policy documentation licensed under “Creative Commons ShareAlike” (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/). You can reuse the content of this document for any purpose but you must release new versions under the same license and please credit Automattic Inc. somewhere. Automattic is not connected with and does not sponsor or endorse ReadyShip or its use of the work.
